In this video, I’ll teach you when
and how to use local variables.
Local variables are temporary variables
that can only be accessed within
the function that defines them.
They are useful when you only need
values within a particular expression.
This is different from rule inputs, which
allow you to pass data to other objects.
Local variables have many uses
in interfaces and expressions.
You can use a local variable to store
a user input that doesn’t need to be
stored elsewhere, like a search term.
Or, you may run into them if you
are reusing a calculated value in
multiple places in an expression.
Local variables are also perfect
for holding a temporary value until
you can save it to a rule input to
use elsewhere in your application.
Let’s look at this short expression that
defines two local variables – one for
the first name and one for the last name.
You may see an expression like this
one in any simple registration form.
To get started, you will first need
the function, a!LocalVariables.
This function allows you to define
as many local variables as you
need to use within an expression.
All local variables must
use the prefix: local.
Following the prefix is
the name of the variable.
It is best to keep the
names short and descriptive.
Once you add the values and your
variables are defined, you can
then use them in your expressions.
In this case, the output is the first
and last name combined, Jane Smith.
Because local variables can only be
used within the expression they’re
defined in, you should generally have
a!LocalVariables at the top so that
you can access and use it throughout
your expression or interface.
A local variable’s type is
determined by the value of the
variable, unlike rule inputs which
have explicitly defined types.
In this example, both local!firstName
and local!lastName are of type text.
Local variables are not limited
to primitive data types.
You can also use other types of variables
or rules like rule inputs, expression
rules, or process variables to define
the value of your local variables.
Here, the variable, vehicle, is defined
using an expression rule that takes
in a vehicle ID as a rule input.
When you enter a valid vehicle
ID, you get an output of the
associated vehicle make and model.
Local variables can also be defined
without an initial value at all.
Often, if your variable is used to
store a temporary input, it will be
defined without a value at first.
In this example, the local variable,
answer, does not have a default value.
However, once the user selects
either true or false, the variable
is assigned the corresponding value.
If you are using local variables
in an interface, you may also need
to consider their refresh behavior.
By default, all variables defined within
the local variables function refresh
when any referenced variables change.
In this vehicle rental form, if the
value of local!borrowDate changes, then
local!returnDate will automatically
update by 7 days at the same time.
You can change this default
refresh behavior using the
!refreshVariable function.
We’ll learn more about refresh
behavior in another video.
Now, let’s recap what
you’ve learned so far.
Local variables define and store
temporary values within an expression.
To define your local variables, you will
need to use the function a!localVariables.
They can be defined with or
without an initial value.
These values refresh when any
referenced variables change.
You can use the refresh variable
function to modify this default behavior.
To learn more about this function, visit
Appian Documentation or check out the
Interface courses at Academy Online.
Thank you for watching, and
I’ll see you in the next one!